本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： Shirley 华青墨 黑色风车 魔法泡泡 向往自由
校对： 唱唱反调  后期： 唱唱反调
各单位请留意一辆红色旅行车
All units be on the lookout for a red station wagon,
通缉犯涉嫌肇事逃逸
wanted in connection to a hit and run...
我靠
Holy crap.
" & * % # @ % ~
Oota nitayan. Oota nitayan.
[加拿大原住民土著语]
嫌犯手里有个女人
Suspect has a woman.
看起来像第一民族的人 我需要支援
Looks like First Nations. I need backup.
第一民族指现今加拿大境内的北美洲原住民及其子孙 因努伊特和梅提斯人除外
别接近他 后援在路上
Don't approach. Backup is en route.
" & * % # @ ~
Weechiwinan! Machie'is!
[还是土著语呦]
" % # @
Machie'is!
他开枪了 立即请求支援
Shots fired, request backup now!
3503出动 三分钟内到达
3503 responding. Three minutes.
" & * % # @
Weechiwinan!
[又是我--加拿大原住民土著语]
" & * % #
Weepimatis!
- & * $ % - 这家伙绝对有问题
- Weechiwinan! - This guy's definitely on something.
要不然他就是疯了 后援不来我绝不下车
Or he's just crazy. I'm not getting out of the car till I've got backup.
- 他们就到了 - # $ $ ^ & *
- They're almost there. - Weechiwinan!
" # $ ^ ^ * &* % $
Wathawee! Weepimatis!
[无处可查的土著语字幕君表示很无力 各位看官请自行领悟]
$ % % " & # @
Machimantoo! Wathawee!
啊
Ah!!
嘿
Hey.
你刚在说梦话
You were talking in your sleep.
是吗
Yeah?
我有没有说...
Did I say...?
你喊了几遍莉斯
Liz. A few times.
- 瑞秋... - 而且你一直在打枕头
- Rach... - And you were fighting with your pillow.
我怕你万一开枪打我
I was worried you might take a shot at me.
今天十六号吗
Is it the 16th today?
快了 现在十五号
15th. Barely.
我得走了 我早班
I've got to go. I'm on early.
等等 瑞秋
Hey, hey. Rach.
瑞秋...
Rach...
立马放下武器
Do it now! Drop that weapon!
2013年11月4日首播
Originally Aired November 4, 2013
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 对上帝发誓我看不见我的脸 #
Swear to God, couldn't see my face
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 注视着一缕灵魂 #
Staring at a ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了么 #
Oh have you seen my ghost
# 感觉到它了么 看到它了么 #
Seen my ghost, seen my ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了么 #
Oh have you seen my ghost
# 它凝视着地面 #
Staring at the ground
心灵缉凶 第二季第6集
受害人应该才二十出头 不是在这被害的
Vic's maybe early twenties. She wasn't killed here.
这里血量不够 她的伤口很深
Not enough blood. She's cut up pretty bad.
疑犯是第一民族的人
Suspect is First Nations.
就现场来看可能是个卡车司机
Possibly a trucker, given the site.
大概是穷人 身份不明
Possibly indigent. No ID on him.
你为什么把他送到圣斯蒂芬医院去
You shipped him over to St. Stephen's. Why?
他在胡言乱语
He was speaking gibberish.
倒在柏油路上抽搐还翻白眼
Collapsed on the tarmac, started convulsing, his eyes rolled back
可是很奇怪 护理人员说并不是癫痫
into his head. Paramedic said it wasn't epilepsy. It was weird.
- 像是昼游症 - 昼游症
- Like a trance state. - A trance state?
我怎么知道 这家伙这么疯狂
What do I know? Guy's acting crazy,
女孩满身是伤还用塑料裹起来
girl's covered in wounds and wrapped in plastic.
所以我把他送到精神病医生那
So I sent him to the shrinks
然后打给了心理科
and called Psych Crimes.
然后我就来了
And here I am.
等着取证
Wait for forensics.
戒指很漂亮 恭喜啦
Nice ring. Congratulations.
- 我认得那家伙吗 - 呃 不认得
- Do I know the guy? - Uh, no.
- 你跟芬顿怎么样 - 挺好的
- How are things with Fenton? - Good.
- 那就好 - 那你要把案子转手了
- Good. - So you handing off?
我跟克莉格拉说过了 疑犯更像精神病犯罪
I spoke to Caligra. Psych Crimes is prime on the suspect.
她要做评测 这个案子我们合作
She wants an evaluation. We work joint on the case.
对攻击者有几成把握
How solid are we on the assailant?
巡警当场抓到的他 车载摄像机有录影
Patrolman caught him in the act. Dashboard camera has it.
- 非他莫属了 - 那是什么意思
- Apparently. - What's that mean?
疑犯用拳头击打巡逻车
Well, the suspect used his fists on the cruiser,
毁掉了录影记录 我们只能看到结尾
damaged the data recording. We have the end.
- 我们会试着修复其余部分 - 看到了啥
- We can try and restore the rest. - What's it show?
疑犯对着树林开枪
Suspect firing into those trees.
- 不是对着巡逻车开枪 - 不是 而且
- Not at the cruiser? - Nope. Meanwhile,
凶器应该是把刀
the murder weapon looks to be that knife,
而不是枪
not a gun.
他对着什么开的枪
What was he shooting at?
^ & ( # % ^ @ " ~
Mati Kitachaak takeeweepatho.
[土著语大哥又开腔了]
@ # % ^ & & * > "
Puskeepatheeta oota aski
[貌似是在祷告的样子 各位看官 你们怎么看]
$^&
igwa
*&%#"@
nitayweechamik
[还是请各位看官自行领会吧]
@ # % & *
kitooteemuk.
@ $ ^ * >
Kawitha oota
# $ % ^ & @ "
moochoomipathi.
你好
Hi.
我是马龙医生
I'm Dr. Malone.
你叫什么
What's your name?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我一会就回来
I'll come back.
你来了 太好了 我们知道受害者身份了
Good, you're here. We have an ID on the victim.
艾伦欧文斯 二十岁 是一名女服务员
Ellen Owens. 20 years old, a waitress.
在她工作的餐馆附近发现的尸体
Body was found near the restaurant where she works.
她被移动过 可能是从附近的树林移过来的
She was moved, possibly from the woods nearby.
警犬已经在搜查了 受害者是第一民族的人
We've got dogs searching. Our victim is First Nations.
疑犯也是 我跟验尸官讲过
And so is our suspect. I spoke with the Coroner.
她身上全是刀伤
There are knife wounds all over her body.
能确定这家伙就是凶手吗
Are we sure this is the guy?
对 轻而易举就能下定论
Looks like a slam dunk, yes.
刀上全是他的指纹
His prints are all over the knife.
我要你去查查该嫌犯跟其他案子是否有关联
I want you to see if we can link this suspect to anyone else.
谁
Who?
这些公路上死的女孩太多了
There are too many dead girls on these highways.
很多都没结案
We don't solve many.
- 我们有查过吗 - 通常我们不做这个
- Do we even try? - That's not our job, normally.
但就此机会或许可以了结一些 我想让你
But this may be a chance to close some. I want you
去调查同一条公路上亟待解决的案子
to look into the active unsolveds along the same highway.
确定这家伙的惯用伎俩
Identify this guy's M.O.,
把所有你认为可能符合的案件档案都整理出来
order up files on anything that you think might fit...
所以我们现在成了你的特遣部队了呗
So you're turning us into a task force?
与此同时
And while you're at it,
我想让你们看看那些相关的铁证悬案卷宗
I want you to look at the relevant cold case files.
我会把它们送到你那去
I'll have them sent over.
- 没有了吧 - 对 就这些
- That all? - Yes. That's all.
把它做好
I want this done right.
伙计 你好像有点粗暴啊
You look a little rough there, buddy.
我没事 里奥
I'm fine, Leo.
行了 我现在去圣斯蒂芬医院
Alright, I'm headed over to St. Stephen's.
去会会这家伙 你来吗
I want to see this guy. You coming?
不了 我得在这工作 我没必要去看他
Nah, I think I'm gonna work here. I don't need to see this one.
- 他是谁 - 不知道
- So who is he? - We don't know.
身份不明 因此也没有
No identification, so no family
家庭或犯罪历史作为参考
or criminal history to reference.
他不说话 因此做不了评测
They can't do the tests because he won't speak.
再告诉我一遍我们怎么知道他是凶手的
Tell me again how we know he did it?
我们逮到他跟那个女孩在一起
We caught him with the girl.
基本算当场擒获
Basically in the act.
- 基本 - 他抱着尸体
- Basically? - He was carrying the body.
杀她的凶器上全是他的指纹
His prints were on the knife that killed her.
他袭击了一辆警车
He assaulted a police car.
当值的警官还说他是个疯子
And the officer on duty said he was psychotic.
我想让你进去看看他
I want you to go in and see him.
你说了他不开口的
You said he won't talk.
他可能会跟你说话
Maybe he'll talk to you.
我有一种感应
I had a reaction.
我当时...
I was...
我还很小的时候 有时会感觉
When I was a little girl I used to feel sometimes
我好像被天使的翅膀抚过
like I had been brushed by an angel's wing.
- 所以他现在成天使了 - 不
- So he's an angel now? - No.
你就进去看看他吧 求你了
Just go in and see him. Please.
当然
Of course.
你有名字吗
You got a name?
你有什么要说的吗
You got anything to say for yourself?
立刻就做 放下武器
Do it now! Drop that weapon!
我觉得那人不是凶手
I don't think that man is a killer.
- 是啊 你觉得他是个天使 - 不是的
- No. You think he's an angel. - No.
我认为...
I think...
不是我认为 我感觉到了一些东西
I don't think. I feel something.
你也感觉到了 我看见了
You felt it too. I saw it.
你就是这么跟你同事说话的吗
You talk to your colleagues like this?
从不
Never.
难道我说错了吗
Am I wrong?
我有个疑问
I have a question.
- 真震惊 - 你入读医学院的时候
- Shocking. - When you started med school,
你知道你会成为一个精神病医生吗
did you know you were going to be a psychiatrist?
- 不知道 -什么改变了你
- No. - What changed your mind?
这些疾病更复杂
The diseases are more complex.
是更大的挑战
Bigger challenge.
癌症是个很大的挑战 不是吗
Cancer's a pretty big challenge, no?
对 确实是
Yes, it is.
你认识的人有得癌症的吗
Someone you know have cancer?
我妈妈 我十五岁时她患病的
My mom. She got it when I was fifteen.
她去世了吗
Did she die?
我妈妈...
My mom...
坚信如果她的信仰足够坚定
believed that if her faith was strong enough,
那么...
that...
上帝会拯救她
God would save her from it.
但他没有
He didn't.
所以我决定去上医学院
So, I decided to go to med school.
- 去抗击癌症 - 是 我最初是这么想的
- To fight cancer. - Yeah, I thought so. At first.
但我其实是想抗击魔鬼
But really I wanted to fight evil.
这很滑稽
Which is funny,
因为我并非成长于信仰魔鬼之家
because I wasn't raised to believe in evil.
而且你很确定精神科医生不该信仰它
And you sure as hell aren't trained to believe in it
我们都不用那个词
as a psychiatrist. We don't even use that word.
但我亲眼见过
But I have looked it in the eye.
癌症根本不知道它在干嘛 它只是吞噬你
Cancer doesn't know what the hell it's doing. It just eats you.
但人知道
People do.
某些人知道
Some of them.
- 你想直面魔鬼 - 是的
- You want to face evil? - Yeah.
有问题吗
Something wrong with that?
没有
No.
只是不是我期待的答案
Just not what I was expecting.
这么说他没向巡逻车开枪
So he never fires at the cruiser.
他只是朝树林里开枪
He only fires into the trees.
她在动
She's moving.
她还活着
She's still alive.
为什么那个巡警没叫救护车
Why didn't the uniform call an ambulance?
波比 查一下无线电抄本
Poppy, check the radio transcription.
- 他打电话叫救护车了吗 - 没有
- Did he call for an ambulance? - Nope.
全弄错了 他是在求助
This is all wrong. He's asking for help.
我同意 他根本不是在威胁警官
I agree. He's not threatening the officer at all.
- 好吧 现在是了 - 可他心烦意乱
- Okay, now he is. - Well, he's distraught.
他怀里有个濒死的女孩 他是在恳求帮助
He's got a girl dying in his arms. He's just pleading for help.
死因是多处刀伤
The cause of death is multiple knife wounds.
那枪绝对没用于受害者
The gun definitely wasn't used on the victim,
- 只用了刀 - 我能看看吗
- only the knife. - Can I see that?
我们有个问题
We've got a problem.
- 什么 - 你看录像了吗
- What? - Have you see this footage?
这警察慌了 我是说
The cop panicked. I mean,
他的报告什么都说明不了 他在掩饰
his report doesn't mean anything, he's covering.
我知道 我已经提请了纪律指控
I know. I already filed discipline charges.
我当时和你现在一样生气
I was as angry as you are right now.
- 你最好处理好 - 至少我们抓到了凶手
- Well, you cover it better. - Well, at least we have the killer.
是吗
Do we?
我认为没抓到 你看过这个了吗
I don't think we do. Have you looked at this?
才送来的
It just came in.
这女孩被折磨过
This girl was tortured.
不管是谁做的 都造成了极端的痛苦
Whoever did this inflicted...extreme suffering.
这些伤口是精心设计的
These wounds are elaborate.
这或许就更容易把他与别的案子联系上
Maybe it'll make it easier to connect him to another case.
这些是我想让你查的案子
These are the cases I want you to look at.
高速公路抛尸 全都是土著女性
Highway body dumps. All Aboriginal women.
看看你能不能把他和这些联系上
See if you can link him to these.
- 克拉拉 做一份侧写 - 没问题
- Clara, I want you to work up a profile. - Absolutely.
侧写是指根据罪犯的行为方式推断出他的心理状态
从而分析出他的性格、生活环境、职业、成长背景等
难道你打算忽略
You just going to ignore everything
我们刚刚说的有关嫌疑人的一切
we just said about the suspect?
录像上的什么都不能使他免罪 艾登
Nothing on that video footage exonerates him, Aidan.
搞清他是谁 找出他与这其中的关联
Find out who he is, link him to these.
- 关联 不是他干的 - 好 那你证明啊
- Link him? He didn't do it. - Okay! Prove it.
你觉得我想要什么 卡娅
What do you think I want, Kaya?
我怎么知道
How would I know?
别这样 你知道的
C'mon, you know.
发生什么了
What's going on?
- 你怎么不去问他们 - 你好吗
- Why don't you ask them? - How you doing,
我是布劳尔警探 这是韦涅夫斯基警探
I'm Detective Brauer, this is Detective Wisnefski.
服务员说你昨晚在这
Waitress says you were here last night?
是的 我吃了晚饭 然后在我的卡车里睡了觉
Yeah, I had dinner. Went to sleep in my truck.
你在附近见过这个人吗
You see this guy around?
当然 见过几次
Sure. Couple of times.
你知道他叫什么吗
You know his name?
不知道 你记得这家伙 对吧 卡娅
Nope. You remember this guy, right, Kaya?
到底发生什么了
What's going on anyway?
我想你们当差的不能随便说吧
I guess you're not at liberty to say, being cops and all.
- 你叫什么 - 雷金纳德斯莱德
- What's your name? - Reginald Slaider.
朋友叫我雷金
Reg to my friends.
谢谢你抽空
Thanks for your time.
这个蠢货就是在妨碍我吃早餐
All this baloney is interfering with me getting my breakfast.
我应该去投诉
I should file a complaint.
艾伦在哪
Where's Ellen?
上次我来的时候她是早班 她还好吗
Last time I was through she had the early shift. She doing okay?
稍等一下 真漂亮
Just a minute, pretty thing...
又一个收藏
That's another keeper.
嘿 我有东西给你
Oh, I got you something.
我想让你帮我保管
I want you to keep this for me.
我不想让任何人的唇
I don't want anyone's lips
碰到它 除非那是你的
touching it unless they're yours.
凶案组那边情况如何 气氛好点了吗
How are things over in Homicide? The air better over there?
他们发布了嫌疑人的照片
They released a photo of the suspect.
- 还没人来认 - 你在餐厅附近问了吗
- No one's come forward yet. - You show it around the restaurant?
问了 有几个人认出了他 但没人知道他的名字
Yeah. Couple of people recognized him, no one knows his name.
- 我们对她了解些什么 - 不多
- What do we know about her? - Not much.
艾伦欧文斯的驾照上的地址过期了
The address on Ellen Owens' driver's license is out of date.
凶案组也很难找到她的近亲
Homicide's having a hard time locating next of kin.
不过 我们找到了这些
But, we did find these
在她工作的地方留下的包里
in a bag that she left at her work.
- 知道是什么吗 - 没头绪
- Any idea what they are? - No idea.
手写体
Handwritten,
符号
symbols.
土著符号
Native symbols?
好吧 我去网上查查 谢谢大家
Okay, I'll do a web search. Thanks, guys.
- 嘿 里奥 - 嗯
- Hey, Leo? - Yeah.
艾登和我今早尝试和嫌疑人对话
Aidan and I tried to talk to the suspect this morning.
运气不佳 你想试试吗
No luck. You want to give it a try?
为什么是我
Why me?
为什么不是你呢
Why not?
嘿 你好
Hey there.
我是里奥
I'm Leo.
我和警察一起工作
I work with the police.
你能告诉我这些是什么吗
Can you tell me what these are?
凯什纳诺
Kay she na no
[请原谅我放荡不羁用音译 因为我不懂土著语]
凯什...
Kay she...
凯什纳诺
Kay she na no?
Kay she na no.
我们
Us.
我的名字叫里奥
My name, Leo.
贝克特
Beckett.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
贝克特
Beckett.
妮萨...
Neetha...
拉扎勒斯 拉扎勒斯基夫
Lazarus. Lazarus Keefe.
阿瓦...
Awa...
艾伦欧文斯 我朋友
Ellen Owens. My friend.
# * $ & @
Niweecheewakan.
朋友...
Friend...
他说他叫拉扎勒斯基夫
He says his name is Lazarus Keefe.
他也就会这么点儿英语
And that's about all the English he knows.
那他说的是什么语言
So what does he speak?
我们还不知道
We don't know yet.
所以我才要求语言学家(支援)
So I requested a linguist.
系统里有他的记录吗
Is he in the system?
波比说没有
Well, Poppy says no.
但唯一一个有记录的拉扎勒斯基夫
But the only Lazarus Keefe on record
曾在一战中服役
served in the first world war.
这倒挺逗 这么说那把枪是一战的
That's funny. The gun used was a World War I issue.
M17左轮手枪
M17 revolver.
也许是他祖父
Maybe his grandfather.
或者太祖父
Great-grandfather?
他还说什么了
Did he say anything else?
还有就是"艾伦欧文斯是我朋友"
"Ellen Owens is my friend." That's it.
- 看来她对他很重要 - 是的
- She was important to him. - Yeah.
这家伙不是卡车司机 他不怎么会说英语
This guy is no trucker. He can barely speak English.
那他是谁
So who is he?
我得回去了 克莉格拉还等着我的侧写呢
I've got to get back. Caligra wants my profile.
你是不是想到什么了
Did you come up with anything?
是的 我还有很多事要做
Yeah. I actually had a lot to work with.
我的侧写完全基于杀手的惯用伎俩
My profile is based solely on the killer's M.O.
太平间的照片
The morgue photos
在艾伦欧文斯的尸体上发现了形状奇特的伤口
show the distinctive wound patterns on Ellen Owens' body.
同样的形状也出现在
This same pattern occurs
她的胃部胸部还有背部
on her stomach, chest and back.
小的辐射圈状切口
Small cuts in radiating circles.
外围浅越往中间越深
Shallow at the perimeter, and then gradually becoming deeper,
直到切口最深的中心点
with the central cut being the deepest.
受害者的腕关节和踝关节都有挫伤
Bruising of the victim's wrists and ankles
说明她曾经被绑过
indicate that she was restrained.
考虑到不断加深的伤口
Consideration has gone into the alternating depths of the wounds
受害者
so that the victim
是失血过多致死
gradually bleeds to death.
这意味着杀手花了很长时间折磨她
That way the killer gets to spend time with her.
当他终于决定杀她时 他刺穿了她的肺
When he was ready to kill her, he punctured her liver.
鉴于切口规则流畅
Note that the cuts are not ragged.
是他精雕细琢出来的
He has executed his wounding with finesse.
他做过这事
He's done this before.
他还会再做
He will do it again.
- 有问题吗 - 这个拉扎勒斯基夫
- Questions? - This Lazarus Keefe,
- 那个嫌疑人 你见过他了 - 见过了
- the suspect, you interviewed him? - I have.
其实我也见过了
Actually, I have too.
通常当你和一个施虐狂共处一室时
Normally when you're in a room with a sadist,
你能感觉到
you can feel it.
你会想要快点儿离开这鬼地方
And you just want to get the hell up out of there.
我们可以把这种感觉称为内心干扰
We call them feelings of visceral disturbance.
是一种处于捕食和被捕时的应激反应引发的
There's a predator/prey response that triggers.
- 我没有过这种感觉 - 我也没有过
- I didn't get that feeling. - I didn't either.
这家伙身高一米九八
This guy is 6'6,
手中持刀 脚边还有一具女孩的尸体
with a knife in his hand and a dead girl at his feet.
显然是他干的
Come on, he did this.
不 我觉得他只是发现了她
No. I think he found her.
我们到底怎么评估他
Where are we with his assessment?
被困住了 我们没法儿跟他交流
It's stalled. We can't talk to him.
你知道我的座右铭 让律师解决
Well, you know my motto. Let the lawyers figure it out.
这可不够好 利兹
That's not good enough, Liz.
是不够好 艾登 但这是工作
Yes, it is, Aidan. That's the job.
我们不一定喜欢它 只是收集证据而已
We don't have to like it. We just collect the evidence.
我们就是在这样做啊
That's what we're doing.
好吧
Okay.
好了 把照片发到网上
Alright, put the photos on the wires.
并传到暴力犯罪的连锁分析系统
And run 'em on ViCLAS too.
你还好吧
You okay?
听着 即使我找对了人 尽管拉扎勒斯基夫
Look, even if I find the right guy, Lazarus Keefe
符合所有合理的怀疑
is all the reasonable doubt that he needs.
我意思是这案子还是毫无头绪
I mean, this case is a mess.
你就是在烦这个
Is that what's bothering you?
是的
Yeah.
怎么样
Anything?
语言学家正在跟进拉扎勒斯基夫
The linguist is working with Lazarus Keefe.
- 但没啥进展 - 又有了个案子
- No progress yet. - We've got another hit.
- 在哪儿 - 帕里湾区
- Where? - Parry Sound.
三周前
Three weeks ago.
帕里湾区 多伦多 圣玛丽...
Parry Sound, Toronto, Sault Ste. Marie...
这是货车走的路线
That's a truck route.
我们能用这案子来澄清拉扎勒斯基夫吗
Can't we use any of this to clear Lazarus Keefe?
还不行
Not yet, no.
- 你知道不是他干的 - 他是在手之鸟
- You know he didn't do it. - He's a bird in hand,
局里不会放他走的
the department's not going to let him go.
尤其是在已经发现了三具尸体的情况下
Not with 3 bodies.
很可能是个极少疏忽的货车司机
A trucker makes sense. Little or no oversight.
有很多犯罪的机会
Lots and lots of opportunity.
别跟在我屁股后面
Get off my butt!
$ % # *
Tamo'win?
* > @ % # $
Namootha kinistootatin
^ ％ # $ @
keegway Kie'toowin.
% * @ #
Namoosa.
我最多能判定是克里族方言
Best I can tell, it's some kind of Cree dialect.
北美印第安人的克里族
说实话
To be honest,
我从没接触过类似这样的语言
I've never come across anything like it.
也就是说你没法儿跟他说话
So you can't talk to him?
一旦一门语言灭绝了...
Once a language dies...
我请你吃早餐 而这里 这儿
I offer to buy you breakfast, and this... this
就是你选的地方 谢谢
is the place that you pick? Thank you.
跟我约会可不破费
I'm a cheap date.
这不是约会 你是在工作
This isn't a date. You're working.
说吧什么目的
What's the angle?
卡娅格雷女士
Miss Kaya Grey
有所隐瞒
knows more than she's saying.
我不明白的是她为什么不说
What I don't get is why she won't talk.
我们是警察 她是土著人
We're cops. She's Native.
也许是这个原因
That might have something to do with it.
嘿
Hey,
你是不是从未停止过工作
you ever stop?
我们发现了和其它一些案件的联系
We found links to some other cases
就在昨晚我走之前
before I left last night.
我们认为你抓错了人
We think you've got the wrong guy.
你是说布莱克认为吗
You mean Black does?
我们都这么觉得
All of us do.
艾登没告诉我该考虑什么
Aidan doesn't tell me what to think.
对你是好事 但你关于那家伙的看法还是不对
Good for you. But you're still wrong about the guy.
我打赌他是她儿子
I bet you he's her son.
我今天早上查了数据库
I checked databases this morning.
有个土著妇女
There's a Native woman
昨晚在桑德贝失踪了
who went missing outside of Thunder Bay last night.
她的车和孩子们
They found her car and her kids
被发现遗弃在一个休息站 时间吻合
abandoned at a rest stop. The timing fits.
发现尸体前这什么也说明不了
It means nothing until there's a body.
这没有任何意义
It means nothing
除非你能找到这个杀手和尸体间的联系
until you can link that body with this killer.
她叫露西麦克
Her name's Lucie Mack.
别这样 我们唯一能做的就是正确处理这件事
Don't do that. All we can do is work it properly.
我在努力啊 戴安
I'm trying, Diane!
但我们现在所知的就是一个第一民族的家伙
But right now all we got is a First Nations guy
跟一把刀和一具尸体
with a knife and a body.
而我们都知道这会让人们怎么想
And we both know how that goes down.
如果他是无辜的 你必须拿出证据
If he is innocent, you will prove it.
如果我拿不出呢
And what if I can't?
艾登 你整晚都在这里
Aidan. You been here all night.
你应该回家
You should go home.
休息一下 整理一下你自己
Get some rest and clean yourself up.
这是命令
That's an order.
遵命 警官
Yes, ma'am.
圣母玛利亚
Mother of God.
嘿
Hey...
这些都是相关的 艾登一夜之间发现的
These are all linked? Aidan turned them up overnight.
大多是暴力犯罪联动系统热点 四个省
Most are ViCLAS hits. Four provinces.
是辆卡车 你们还认为我们不对
It's a trucker. You guys still think we're wrong?
我最好记录下
I better check in.
一会见
I'll see you later.
关于艾伦我还有些问题
I've got a few more questions about Ellen.
我跟你没什么好说的
I don't have anything to say to you.
你画的画很漂亮
That's a pretty great drawing you've got there.
我能仔细看看吗
Can I see it close up?
这是你的名字吗
Is that your name?
以利亚
Elijah?
这个漂亮的天使是谁
Who's the beautiful angel?
- 是妈妈 - 艾伦妈妈
- That's Mommy. - Mommy Ellen?
以利亚 把你的午饭吃完
Elijah! Finish your lunch.
他是艾伦欧文斯的儿子
He's Ellen Owens' son.
你不觉得你应该早告诉我们吗
You don't think you should have told us that?
为什么 那样你就能把他带走了是吗
Why? So you can take him away?
必须通知艾伦妈妈的家人
Ellen's family needs to be informed.
由他们决定孩子的命运
It's their decision what happens to the boy...
我就是他的家人
I'm his family.
艾伦是我妹妹
Ellen is my sister.
别来打扰我们
Leave us alone.
我做不到
I can't do that.
必须有人去认领艾伦的尸体
Someone needs to claim Ellen's body.
以利亚 收拾好你的东西 好吗
Elijah? You get your things together, okay?
你好 我是侦缉警长艾登布莱克 公安局的
Hi, it's Detective Sergeant Aidan Black, Metro Police.
我之前打过电话询问过一名失踪女士
I called earlier about a woman who's missing.
露西麦克
Lucie Mack.
有进一步消息吗
Have you heard anything further?
好的 如果有任何消息 请通知我
Alright, well, get back to me if there's anything... anything at all.
嘿 你睡觉了吗
Hey. Did you get any sleep?
我没事
I'm fine.
艾登
Aidan...
Aidan?
这是以利亚欧文斯 艾伦的儿子
This is Elijah Owens. Ellen's son.
抱歉 这是艾登的办公桌
I'm sorry. This is Aidan's desk.
没关系 请坐
No. That's okay, that's okay. Sit.
你在画什么
What are you drawing?
我还没想好
I don't know yet.
怎么不试试这些画笔
Why don't you try these?
如果你想要可以留着
You can keep them if you like them.
谢谢
Thank you.
艾登
Aidan.
你介意我跟你一起进去与卡娅格雷谈谈吗
Would you mind if I came in and talked to Kaya Grey with you?
抱歉
Yeah, sorry...
我今天不在状态
I'm a little off today.
我知道
I know.
今天是十六号
It's the 16th today.
一年前的今天我害死了一个孩子
A year ago I got a kid killed.
我们里面见
Want to meet me in there?
好的
Yeah. Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们像对待罪犯一般对待我
You treat me like I'm some kind of criminal!
抱歉 没有空房间了
I'm sorry. There's no other room available...
- 以利亚在哪里 - 他没事 在隔壁
- Where is Elijah? - He's okay. He's just next door.
卡娅
Kaya,
我们会安排把你妹妹的尸体送去殡仪馆
we'll arrange to have your sister's body moved to a funeral home.
你选一个
You choose one.
你需要的话我可以帮你
I can help you if you want.
我想跟你谈谈拉扎勒斯基夫
I want to talk to you about Lazarus Keefe.
艾伦怎么认识他的
How did Ellen know him?
他曾经是我们的朋友
He was our friend.
他一直陪着我们 他没有杀艾伦
He was always there for us. He didn't kill Ellen.
对 我相信不是他干的
No, I don't believe he did.
我搭档也是这么认为的
My partner doesn't believe so either.
卡娅 我需要你跟他谈谈
Kaya, I need you to talk to him.
我们得查明那天晚上发生了什么
We need to find out what happened that night.
我没法跟他讲话
I can't talk to him.
我跟他没法交流
I don't speak his language.
但是你一定认识什么人
But you must know someone...
没人能跟他交流
There's no one who speaks his language.
他是最后一个
He's the last.
拉扎勒斯跟他的高曾祖父住在一起
Lazarus lived with his great-great-grandfather.
在他小时候这个老先生带他去了北方
The old man took him up north when he was a boy.
他不想让他上学 他们与世隔绝
He didn't want him in school. They lived there by themselves.
他死时 拉扎勒斯很孤独
When he died, Lazarus was alone.
但是艾伦在研究他的语言
But Ellen was learning his language.
是的
Yes.
拉扎勒斯有人聊天
And Lazarus had someone to talk to.
他靠什么过活
But how does he live?
他住在哪里
Where does he live?
拉扎勒斯没活着
Lazarus doesn't live.
他死了
He's a dead man.
卡娅认为拉扎勒斯徘徊在
Kaya believes that Lazarus moves between the worlds
生死之间的世界
of the living and the dead.
她认为他能与鬼魂对话
She believes he communicates with spirits.
评估组有不同的看法
The assessment team have a different take.
他们认为他有创伤后精神紧张性障碍
They think he has PTSD.
很符合
It fits.
他饱受失眠和焦虑困扰
He suffers from sleeplessness, anxiety.
护士们无数次
The nurses have recorded
见到他神志昏迷
numerous moments when he seems to fall into a trance.
他们也见到过
They've also observed
他突然惊慌失措的样子
sudden startling,
似乎他听到或者看到什么
as if he's hearing or seeing things.
- 幻觉 - 创伤后精神紧张性障碍有两种
- Hallucinations.- There are two types of PTSD.
你的情况 由灾难性的事件引起的
Yours, brought on by a sudden catastrophic event.
而他的情况 日益积累的精神创伤
And his, cumulative strain trauma.
他所有的人生经历
The sum total of his life experience,
失去高曾祖父
the loss of his great-great-grandfather,
语言壁垒
language barrier,
寂寞
the loneliness,
艾伦欧文斯的死亡
the death of Ellen Owens...
其他还有多少
And how many others?
收到地方居民报告
We got a report in from the Provincials.
发现了一具尸体
Found a body.
身份鉴定定为露西麦克
Identified as Lucie Mack.
她被折磨了吗
Was she tortured?
手法相同 是我们要找的人
Same pattern. It's our guy.
有什么发现吗
Did they find anything?
当地居民忘记遮盖现场 昨晚下雨了
Locals forgot to tent the scene. Rained last night.
现场本来有车轮印 但已经消失了
There were tire tracks,but now they're gone.
我们发现一具尸体
We've got a body.
露西麦克
Lucie Mack.
居民搞砸了犯罪现场 但是没关系
Locals screwed up the crime scene, but it doesn't matter.
拉扎勒斯基夫已经被排除嫌疑
Lazarus Keefe is eliminated as a suspect.
- 他可能有帮凶 - 与侧写不符
- He could have an accomplice. - Doesn't fit the profile.
也不可能是模仿的 我们隐瞒了伤害形态
It can't be a copycat, we've held back the wound pattern.
- 好的 - 他是无辜的
- Okay. - He's innocent.
- 我们差点判他入狱 - 不
- And we nearly sent him down.- No.
你刚救他免于牢狱之灾
You just saved him from that.
什么
What?
我是说 他们都不能遮盖下犯罪现场吗
I mean, they couldn't even tent the crime scene?
我们尽力而为
We do what we can.
我会释放拉扎勒斯基夫
I will get Lazarus Keefe released.
做得好
Good work.
抱歉
Excuse me.
挨拳头的又不是我
Wasn't me you punched.
你多久没睡觉了
How long has it been since you slept?
我睡不着
I can't sleep...
我总是忘不了
I'm on the bus again.
你说已经1年了吧
One year, you said?
也不算是很长时间
That's not a lot of time.
这种感觉不会消失
It doesn't go away.
你必须习惯它
You learn to live with it.
这里
There.
看到了吗
See?
只是墙上的一个洞而已
It's just a hole in the wall.
我得走了 他没事吧
Listen, I gotta go. Is he going to be okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
把当前所有的发现写份书面报告给我
I want detailed written reports of your recent findings,
我要把它们
and I will pass them on
交给省级相关机关以及皇家骑警队
to the provincial authorities and the RCMP.
然后呢
And then what?
他们会继续调查
Homicide will continue their investigation
艾伦欧文斯一案的凶手 拜托快点整理吧
into Ellen Owens' murder. Pack it up, please.
怎么了
What's going on?
心理科已为疑犯洗脱嫌疑
Psych Crimes has cleared the suspect.
我们要准备移交工作
We're handing off.
移交给谁
Handing off to who?
- 问得好 - 这不关我们的事了 里奥
- Good question. - It's out of our hands, Leo.
剩下的案子不在我们的管辖范围内
The other cases are out of our jurisdiction.
我想真正的凶手也不在
The killer probably is too.
快点 赶紧整理吧
Come on, pack it up.
我准备走了 你呢
Alright, I'm going. You too.
这些我们可以明天早上再整理
We'll finish this in the morning.
- 我在等布劳尔 - 没事吧
- I'm waiting for Brauer. - Things good?
嗯 案子是...
Yeah. Case is...
不 以前是牵绊
was getting in the way.
还会有新的案子的
There'll be another one.
- 我是布莱克 请留言 - 艾登
- This is Black. Leave a message. - Aidan,
我发现了相关案子的一份目击者笔录
I just found a witness report on one of the linked cases.
之前被我们忽略了
It was misfiled.
目击者说最后一次看到受害人时
Witness fingered a trucker
提到个卡车司机
last seen with the victim.
司机的名字是雷金纳德斯莱德 艾伦被杀那晚
His name is Reginald Slaider. He was at the restaurant
他在那家餐厅 我跟他的雇主确认过了
the night Ellen was murdered. I just checked with his employer,
他的行驶路线完全符合我们的假设
and his routes fit our pattern.
猜猜目击者是谁
Guess who the witness was?
是卡娅格雷 我现在就去餐厅
Kaya Grey. I'm headed to the restaurant now.
没错 是我做的笔录
Yes, I made the report.
为什么你没告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us?
做完笔录就没有下文了
Nothing happened then.
现在又有什么区别吗
Why would it be any different now?
但你知道我们正在调查...
But it was followed up...
我当然知道 就跟这次一样
Sure it was. Just like this time.
你们根本就没调查清楚 你们抓住了拉扎勒斯
No, you didn't 'follow up.' You had Lazarus.
你们已经准备让他当替罪羊了
You were all ready to hang it on him.
- 卡娅... - 滚
- Kaya... - Go to hell.
我是布莱克 请留言
This is Black. Leave a message.
艾登 快来载货汽车停车场 记得带上支援
Aidan. Get over to the truck stop right away, and bring backup..
雷金纳德斯莱德 他就在这里
Reg Slaider. He's here.
我是艾登布莱克警探
Detective Aidan Black.
你是雷金纳德斯莱德
You Reginald Slaider?
没错 有事吗
Yeah. So?
你怎么会有个这么蠢的名字
How'd you get such a stupid name?
你父亲帮你取的吗
From your dad?
不 你根本不知道你父亲是谁 是吗
No, you wouldn't know who your father is, would you?
你 你想知道些什么
You, uh, you want something?
不久前有一份目击者笔录
There was a witness came forward a while back.
关于你之前搭载的一个女孩儿的
About a girl you gave a ride to.
目击者吗 还真是有趣
A witness? Well, that is interesting.
之前也有一个不知道名字的白痴警官
Once upon a time, there was an Officer Joe Idiot
问过我同样的问题
asked me some questions.
你问的是同一个女孩儿吗 蠢蛋警官
You asking about the same girl, Officer A-hole?
她叫查斯媞 不是你们问的那个
Her name was Chastity. She wasn't.
在路边我就让她下车了
I dropped her off. Side of the road.
当时周围一个人都没有 但是她坚持要下车
No one around for miles, but she wanted out.
- 当时她还活着吗 - 我记得是的
- Was she alive? - Far as I recall.
但是据那个警官所说
Not for long, though.
她不久之后就死了
According to the officer.
那露西麦克呢
What about Lucie Mack?
被绑架的印度少妇 还有两个孩子的那个
Indian chick. Kidnapped. Couple kids?
没错
That's right.
报纸上登了
That was in the paper.
或许我见过她
Maybe I saw her.
是吗 你这么了解
Yeah, you were up that way?
没错 不过她跟其他人一样
I was. But, she'd be like the rest of them.
不合身的内衣 廉价的香水 还有纹身
Underwear that doesn't match. Cheap perfume. Tattoos.
你喜欢那样的女孩吗
You like girls like that?
是她们喜欢我
They like me.
你杀过人没有
You ever kill anyone?
哦 你的表情已经告诉我了
Well, I bet that's something.
当你的双手感受到他们温热的鲜血
You feel their blood warm on your hands.
闻着就像潮湿的金属味
That wet metal smell of it.
看着他们痛苦挣扎
Something to watch them suffer.
听着他们的祈求声
Hear them beg.
你是什么感觉
How'd that make you feel?
说说看吧
Tell me.
我真的非常想知道
'Cause, I'd like to know.
尿完了回来找我
Come back and see me after you take your piss.
我可不是要去卫生间 雷金
Yeah, I'm not going to the bathroom, Reg,
我只是要去检查你的装备
I'm going to search your rig.
逮捕令已经到了
Warrant just arrived.
盯着他 看好门
Keep an eye on him. Watch the door.
我今天早上捡了一辆空拖车
I just picked up an empty trailer this morning.
他们说的那个目击者是谁 卡娅
Who's that witness they're talking about, Kaya?
是你吗
That you?
我听说他们已经找到了凶手
I hear they got the guy that did it.
那让你觉得心里好受些了吗
That puts your mind at rest.
没错
Yeah.
我从后面进
I'll take the back.
放下刀 雷金 放下刀
Hey! Put it down, Reg, put it down.
- 现在就放下 - 照他说的做 斯莱德
- Drop it! Now! - Do it, Slaider.
是她 把她铐起来
Arrest her! Put the cuffs on her!
# $ & @
Kitooteemuk.
你为什么没告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us?
我不相信你们
I don't trust you.
我只相信拉扎勒斯
I trust Lazarus.
你策划了这一切 你知道是雷金做的
You planned this. You knew about Reg.
拉扎勒斯来这里就是为了杀他
Lazarus came here to kill him.
你应该告诉我们的
You should've talked to us.
我跟你们说了雷金会死吗
Would Reg be dead if I did?
那艾伦呢
Would Ellen?
你们那帮人都没有救艾伦斯
Yes. You people don't save Ellens.
她会怎么样
What's going to happen to her?
至少会被判袭击的罪名
She'll get assault. At least.
在量刑时应该要考虑到
Reg Slaider tortured these people.
雷金纳德斯莱德的所作所为
That should count for something.
嗯 也许她因此会得到一些同情 但是...
Well, she'll get some sympathy, but...
不公平的是他会获得最大量刑
Odds are he'll get the maximum.
至少他的目的已经达到了
He's done what he came for.
# 我无所畏惧 #
I fought a careless way
# 目标明确 #
Indicated
# 我带来了这首歌 #
I bought the song
# 它却从未被吟唱过 #
But it never got played
# 它已渐渐被遗忘 #
That's fading
# 但我们始终同行 #
But we're coming up
# 陌生的人们 #
Strangers